Mallesh Madapathi

Montreal, Quebec, Canada



malleshmadapathi@outlook.com



+14388214434



linkedin.com/in/malleshmadapathi



https://mplusm.github.io/

Summary

Actively looking for new opportunities in

Software development, UI/UX. 3 years experience in hybrid environment

(software development and production support) and one year designing experience.

Languages: Python, Machine Learning, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, solid understanding of node.js.

Angular, RESTful APIs, vue.js

Databases: SQL, Solid understanding of MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB

UI/UX: Adobe CC, wireframes, graphic designing in Adobe

Understanding of tools: Github, OAuth, XCode, Android Studio, Docker, Jupyter notebook, Eclipse IDE, Active Directory,

0365, Microsoft Exchange, ServiceNow, Adobe Creative Cloud, Linux command line tools.

Experience

cgi Technical Consultant

CGI

Oct 2018 - Jul 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Client: BMO Financial Group | Platforms supported: BMO Canada, US, Harris Bank, M&I

Programmer Analyst for various banking applications which were written in Java, Python, JavaScript,

C#(.NET), C++ on Windows Platform.

Provides first level remote support to internal and external clients for a wide variety of technical, network and operating systems, applications, hardware, mobile devices, and wireless technology and telephony; investigates, troubleshoots and resolves incidents and requests; refers unresolved matters to appropriate technical staff.



UI/UX Designer

Bishop's University

Apr 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 5 months)

 $Free lanced \ as \ UI/UX, Layout \ editor \ for \ student \ run \ 70 yr \ old \ campus \ newspaper/Magazine \ which \ is \ bi-weekly.$

Responsibilities include:

Designing, editing, formatting, planning the bi-weekly edition

Collaboration with all the various editors for implementing, designing the edition

Tools used: Adobe Indesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver

The newspaper can be found on this link https://issuu.com/thecampus



Android Developer

Hafyaline

Jun 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year 5 months)

Hafyaline is an online doctor consulting application, which is used to solve patient problems, book appointments and also used to search for blood donors as well.

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.online.hafya.user&hl=en

Worked on android app development including design, development and testing. Worked on Activities, Fragments, Services, UI Development, Audio and Video Streaming. Worked on adding Firebase Analytics, Push Notifications (FCM) to an android app.

Built a Video calling app using WebRTC and Sinch library. Integrating 3rd party libraries. Knowledge in using SQLite Database.

Education



Bishop's University

Master's degree, Computer Science

2018 - 2020

Master's Degree (Course-based program) Data Science, Machine learning, AI, Software Engineering

Transcript: (Winter 2018 - Winter 2020) CS515: Concurrent and real time systems

CS557: Database software Design

CS564: Computer Networks and distributed algorithms

CS596: Research topics in Computer science - AI, Automation

CS501: The Internet of Things CS509: Pattern Recognition CS560: Software Engineering CS503: Data Visualization

CS504: Programming Languages for Data Analytics

CS563: Image Analysis - Python, openCV

CS590: Master Project valid 9 credits in AI, Object recognition, NLP, Graph Theory models

CS505: Data Mining

CS507: Statistical Learning

CS520: Advanced Topics in Software

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Machine Learning • Data Visualization • Android Development • Software Development • Web Development • Front-end Development • Data Structures • Algorithms • Data Analysis